Mykhaylo-Ivan Filipenko

QA Automation Engineer

29F Ridlerstr Muenchen, 80339 +49 163 8417380 mykhailo.filipenko@gmail.com LinkedIn, GitHub

SUMMARY

I am an Automation QA with a long-standing background in the corresponding field. Throughout my career, I have perfected my skills in test-cases automation using Java, TestNg, and Maven. Also, I have tremendous experience in API test automation with RestAssured technology. I am a self-motivated and confident person with good communication, analytical, problem-solving, and troubleshooting skills.

EXPERIENCE

First Ukrainian International Bank, Lviv — Automation QA

NOVEMBER 2021 - JUNE 2022

Contributing to the general QA process, participating in brainstorming sessions, and my ideas were accepted and developed by the team. I was doing UI/API/Corezoid automation process which allows a team to know every time if services are alive.

GlobalLogic, Lviv — Junior Automation QA (Java)

OCTOBER 2019 - NOVEMBER 2021

Wrote and maintained UI frameworks for IOS and Web that allows the QA team to know if all services altogether work correctly. I communicated with customers daily and participated in general QA and developer meetings.

EDUCATION

Lviv Polytechnic National University, Lviv — Bachelor

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2021

Finished bachelor's degree in computer science at Lviv National Polytechnic University. Avg.: 89.5/100 (Analog of 1.7 in Germany).

PROJECTS

Wiki automation — Small framework for tests automation

Two years ago I implemented a framework for UI tests automation. The main purpose of this pet project was to find out how to build my project from zero. After completing wiki automation I used the gained knowledge at work.

SKILLS

Platforms: Web, Android, iOS.

Java: Core, Maven, TestNg, Selenium, Appium, RestAssured.

C++: STL, algorithms.

Python: Django, Matplotlib, CV, NumPy.

General: OOP, Git, TestRail, Scrum, Allure, problem solving, API/Web/Mobile testing, Teamwork.

AWARDS

Participant at ½ ICPC World finals.

Wrote my framework for API testing for a Ukrainian bank.

Got 95+% of stable automated UI tests.

Karate World Cup medalist, ex-member of Ukrainian national team.

INTERESTS

Sport, traveling, reading, and teaching.

LANGUAGES

English (B2), German (A2), Ukrainian.